Register of the Aleksandr Sergeevich Pushkin Subject Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Aleksandr Sergeevich Pushkin subject collection,
1935-1972
2000C66
2 microfilm reels (0.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, printed matter, and miscellany, relating to the Russian writer Aleksandr Pushkin.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains rare books, clippings, special issues of periodicals and typescripts relating to the life, writings and legacy of Aleksandr Pushkin. Much of the material is connected with anniversary celebrations (1937 - 100 years of his death, and 1949 - 150 years of his birth).
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco, as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Pushkin, Aleksandr Sergeevich, 1799-1837.; Russian literature.; Russia.
Series Description
- General File, 1935-1972. (Box 1)
  Articles, books, clippings, special issues of periodicals, scrapbooks and writings, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Oversize File, 1936-1949. (Box 2-3)
  Commemorative newspaper issues and scrapbooks, composed primarily of clippings and correspondence
Container List
- GENERAL FILE, 1935-1972 (Box 1)
  - Booklets (Folder 1: 1)
  - Books. (Folder 1: 2)
    Includes Memorial des festivités qui ont eu lieu à Genève en 1937 pour célébrer le centenaire de la mort du poète Alexandre Pouchkine (Geneva, 1937)
  - Clippings (Folder 1: 3-4)
  - Minutes of meetings of the Pushkin Committee in Paris, 1936-1937 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Periodical issues (Folder 1: 6)
  - Programs (Folder 1: 7)
  - Writings
    - Brazol', Boris, "Baironizm Pushkina," n.d. (Folder 1: 8)
      Typescript
    - Nelidova-Fiveiskaia, Lidiia, "A. S. Pushkin," 1948 June 2. (Folder 1: 9)
    - Tsurikov, N. A., "Zavety Pushkina," n.d. (Folder 1: 10)
    - Zaitsev, K. I., "Smert' Pushkina," 1937. (Folder 1: 11)
      Printed copy
  - Miscellany. (Folder 1: 12)
    Includes jubilee brochures, flyers, instructions for compiling a Pushkin bibliography, postcards, and other matter
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1936-1949. (Box 2)
  - Commemorative newspaper issues (Folder 2: 1)
  - Scrapbooks (Folder 2: 2-3)
  - Scrapbooks (Box-folder 3: 1-3)